Okay, module three, financial literacy.
This one is, it may seem overwhelming,
it may seem tough to really think about your finances
like that as opposed to financial aid,
but it's good to really dissect that.
So the objectives here, read a financial aid award letter,
identify what's a grant, what's a loan,
what you have to return,
what you may not work study to explain
between the difference between subsidized and unsubsidized.
Build a monthly budget, using your own situation,
identify common financial scams.
Remember FAFSA is free.
So you should not be getting any emails about,
hey, I'll pay to do your FAFSA because it's already free.
Yeah, budgeting is extremely important.
I've found myself very broke from time to time
in my undergraduate time, freshman year,
but there are a lot of things with budgeting and finances
that once you really write it down and get it down,
you know how much you owe,
you know how much money you have left over per the week,
how much money you have for groceries.
You know, if you want to even think about our part-time job,
I've had plenty, more than a handful of part-time jobs
in college.
I've worked at least three or four different work studies.
I've had a part-time job at it as a Boba barista.
I know what it's like to be struggling financially,
especially during college,
not knowing if you have enough money for certain things.
So it's very important.
I wish I had this lesson as well, but make sure you budget,
make sure you write down what your finances are,
you know, in the previous lesson about your campus resource,
you know, reading your financial aid plan,
going to the financial aid center of your college
and finding out what money may be free to you,
what money you have to get back,
you know, what your refund is looking like
if you even get a refund at all.
But, you know, don't just blow it all in one place.
That's for sure.
Make sure you budget,
make sure you allocate it for the semester if you need,
and then go from there.
So yeah, I hope this lesson serves as a great purpose for you guys.